

# Mehmet Onur Üstünel

iOS Developer

## **SKILLS**

- OOP GIT (VCS) SOLID PRENCIPLES
- MVP MVVM
   CORE DATA REALM
- COCOAPODS SPM RESTful API JIRA
- CONCURRENCY
   CORE ANIMATION
- FIREBASE
   CORE LOCATION
   CHARTS
- ALAMOFIRE NETWORKING JWT TOKEN
- AES ENCRYPTION LOTTIE

## **HOBBIES & INTERESTS**









Web:





## CONTACT

Birthday: 01.01.1994

Phone: +90 542 256 98 41

e-mail: ustunel.onur@gmail.com LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/onurustunel GitHub: github.com/onurustunel

onurustunel.github.io

#### **ABOUT ME**

I was born in 1994 in Turkey. I took courses in Mathematics and Computer Science at university. After graduating with a high GPA, I wanted to focus on the mobile software development and turned to the iOS development.

I started working in the mobile software industry as a freelance iOS developer and worked as a freelancer on 3 different projects. The last application I worked for freelance was a social media application with a larger user base than the others, with live video broadcasting. It was written with MVVM architecture and Firebase was used on the backend.

Then I started working full time as an iOS developer in one of the biggest companies in Turkey. With a small team in this company, I developed an iOS application to be used by the company's executives. I was the only iOS developer on the team and the iOS version of the app was developed entirely by me. In the majority of the application, GET and POST operations were performed with the Rest API and the responses from these requests were displayed to the user in the application interface. In the application, some data is encrypted with AES for security purposes. Core Data was used as the database so that the application can also work offline.

Then I started working as an iOS Developer at Huawei, one of the world's largest technology companies, where I am currently working. Here, I am working on the LinkNow project with a super-app concept, video conferencing, instant messaging, file sharing and online classroom features. I took an active role in the CI/CD process with Jenkins for two months. I was awarded in my company as a "Future Star" at the end of the year 2021. I made technical interviews with about 30 candidates who wanted to work at Huawei.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

• Huawei - iOS Developer / August 2021 - Present

I am working on LinkNow Project in Huawei. LinkNow integrates functions such as instant communication, video conferencing, documents, cloud space, classroom and team groups to build a one-stop platform for efficient communication and collaboration for individuals, families, and organizations. I mostly worked on instant messaging module. I took an active role in the CI/CD process with Jenkins for two months. I made technical interviews with about 30 candidates who wanted to work at Huawei. I was awarded as a "Future Star" at the end of the year 2021.

• Cengiz Holding - iOS Developer / October 2020 - August 2021

I developed a native iOS app for Cengiz Holding company's executives which has more than 50.000 employees in Turkey. I was the only iOS developer on the team and the iOS version of the app was developed entirely by me. In most of the application, network requests were made with URLSession and the responses were displayed to the user in the user interface. Some critical data were encrypted with AES for security purposes. Core Data was used as the database so that the application can also work offline.

Bionluk Freelance iOS Developer / January 2019 - October 2020
I worked as a freelancer on 3 different projects. The last project I was working on was one that had a larger user base than the other two projects, and I took part in this project the longest. During the time I worked on this project, I gained a lot of experience on Core iOS Frameworks. This application was a native iOS application, which included live broadcast viewing and online ticket purchasing features, written with MVVM architecture and using Firebase on the backend.

• VenusWed Online Photography and Video Service / 2017 - 2018

I have developed a website where those who come to Turkey from abroad for touristic purposes can reach photographers and make reservations. This site was viewed from 86 countries and more than 60 bookings were made.

## **EDUCATION**

Bachelor's Degree / 2011 - 2015
 Aksaray University (*Turkey*)

**Department of Mathematics** (GPA: 3.38 / 4.00)

♦ Study Abroad (Erasmus) / 2014

Bialystok University of Technology (*Poland*)

Computer Science

Associate Degree / 2015 - 2017
 Anadolu University (Turkey)

**Photography and Videography Department**